你醒了吗
You awake?
怎么了
Why?
我想跟你做了
Redneck foreplay.
宝贝  你醒了吗
Hey, baby, you awake?
还是你想让我来唤醒你
Or, would you like to get awake?
让你舒舒服服地醒来
Good and awake?
现在不想
Mmm... not now.
你上班要迟到了吧
Aren't you late for work anyway?
请了一天假
Took the day off.
爸爸的意思
Dad's idea.
要带丹尼尔去吃午餐吗
Taking Daniel to lunch today?
去曼斯菲尔德的那家乡村厨房
Going to the Country Kitchen in Mansfield.
去曼斯菲尔德吗
Mansfield?
这附近的人都盯着我们呢
Everybody be watchin' us around here.
如果我们在波利这边吃午餐
You know, it's too much of a statement
就会跟公告似的
if we go out to lunch in Pawley,
好像我们已经是好兄弟了
like we're all of a sudden buddy-buddy, you know?
公告
Statement?
就是昭告天下了  懂吗
In everybody's face, you know?
但我想要像瑞典一样
I wanna be a little like Sweden.
左右逢迎
Sell goods to both sides.
亲爱的  你不是该站在他那边吗
Honey, shouldn't you be on his side?
什么
Huh?
你不是应该站在他那边吗
Shouldn't you be on his side?
不
No.
我应该站在我们这边
I should be on our side,
站对生意有利的一边
as in save the damn business side.
好像这个家里只有我懂这个道理
Nobody seems to understand that but me.
丹尼尔
Daniel?
丹尼尔  亲爱的  我们回来了
Daniel, honey, we're home.
他不在家里
He's not here.
你就一点都不担心吗
Aren't you even a little concerned?
担心
Concerned?
他被关了二十年
He was locked up for 20 years,
妈  而且他已经两天没回家了
mother, and he's been out two days,
现在也不在
and now he's not here.
没有留字条  什么都没有
No note, nothin'.
你想要我怎么做  亲爱的
Well, what do you want me to do about it, honey?
妈  我不要你做什么
I don't want you to do anything, mother.
煮饭去吧
Just cook.
你好
Hello.
我去外面等你
I'll meet ya outside.
乔恩打来的
It's John.
我们要去找他
We're gonna go look for him.
妈  这里有人想要丹尼尔的命啊
There are people around here, mom, who wanna see Daniel dead,
要不是害怕背官司
people who would do it themselves,
他们甚至会自己动手
if they thought they could get away with it.
我们至少该给他随便买部手机吧
We should at least get him a cheap phone.
我妈快把我逼疯了
My mother is driving me crazy.
她做什么了
What's she doing?
什么都没
Nothing.
真心是什么都没做
Absolutely nothing.
走吧
Let's go.
好吧
Uh, okay.
你好
Hello.
你好  先生
Hello, Sir.
聪明水  纯净水
这个真的有用吗
Does this work?
没那么神吧
Not miracles, I would think.
一共3.16美元  先生
That'll be $3.16, Sir.
先生
Sir?
4.19美元
Four-nineteen.
谢谢惠顾  先生
Thank you, Sir.
霍顿重获自由
他在那里
There he is.
靠边停
Oh, pull over.
他现在是什么感受
What's that like?
我无法想象
I can't imagine.
他在吃什么
What's he eatin'?
看起来像是糖果条什么的
Looks like a candy bar or somethin'.
他只是在感受青草绿地
He's just feeling the grass.
我们这样不太好是吧
This isn't very cool, is it?
是不太好
Not on our part, no.
我们得带他回家吧
Shouldn't we take him home?
我觉得我们应该离开
I think we should just leave, you know?
但你不了解这个镇
Yeah, but you don't know this town.
阿曼莎  我们不能整天跟着他
Amantha, we can't follow him around for the whole day.
我知道  但是
I know, but--
不
No.
不  你是对的
No, you're-you're right.
看啊  是丹尼尔
Look, it's Daniel!
乔恩才刚到这儿
John just got here!
我们等会儿见
We'll see ya later!
有人吗
Hello?
有人在家吗
Anybody home?
有人吗
Hello?
妈
Mom?
在这里
In here.
你还好吗
You feeling all right?
只是在休息
Resting.
其他人呢
So, where's everybody else at?
都出去了
Out.
我是来带丹尼尔去吃午餐的
I was gonna take Daniel to lunch.
我早到了  所以...
I got here early, so--
很高兴你能这么做  小泰
That's a sweet gesture, Teddy.
要我给你拿点儿什么吗
Can I get you something?
阿司匹林  胃片
Aspirin-- Tums?
不用了
No.
不用  我没事
No, I'm fine.
只是...
Just--
好吧
Okay.
厨房柜子上还有些牛奶  肉什么的
There's some stuff on the counter, um, milk and meat.
我帮你放到冰箱里可以吗
Should I just put those things in the fridge?
好  真好
Yeah. That'd be nice.
谢谢你  小泰
Thank you, Teddy.
不用  妈
Okay, mom.
抱歉
Uh, sorry.
珍妮特  老是记不住
Janet, I keep forgetting.
你可以叫我妈  小泰
Oh, you can call me mom, Teddy.
我觉得没关系
I think that's all right.
我也不知道
I don't know.
不然这样吧
I'll tell you what.
他在的时候  我叫你珍妮特
How about when he's around, I'll call you "Janet,"
他不在时叫妈
and "Mom" when he's not?
作为我们的小秘密
It'll be our little secret.
那样很好  小泰
I'd like that, Teddy.
你要待一整星期吗
You staying the whole week?
几天而已
Oh, just a few days.
希望能在离开前见检察官一面
Try to get the DA to meet with me while I'm in town.
在他们开始行动之前我什么都做不了
There's not much to do here until they make their move.
陪审团还是向着我们的吗
Justice Row still feel positive about everything?
当然
Of course.
那记者发布会呢
What about the press conference?
-好吧  -你说吧  我能接受
- Well, uh-- - I can take it.
大家都知道这一切对丹尼尔来说很艰难
Everyone knows how hard it must be for Daniel,
-但都希望他能表现得  -正常一点
- but we were hoping he could be a little more-- - Normal?
不要那么神秘
Less esoteric.
他的情况的确很特殊
Well, he does have a unique situation.
很明显
So, by definition--
我知道
I know.
我们都理解
We understand.
我担心的是公众的反应
It's the public I'm worried about.
第一印象很重要
You know, first impressions.
-他就是那样  乔恩  -我知道
- He is who he is, Jon. - I know.
但他也得更主动一点
But, at some point, he's gonna have to be more proactive.
时不时强调一下自己是无辜的
You know, it wouldn't hurt for him to
也没有什么害处
declare his innocence from time to time.
我们一定要现在讨论这件事吗
Do we have to talk about this, right now?
不
No.
不用
抱歉
I'm sorry.
我只是  我只是觉得
I just... I just thought
咱俩不必一直这么规规矩矩的
we'd all get some time off for good behavior.
在我们付出那么多努力救他出来后
To gear up so quickly,
在他经历了那么多后
after all it took to get him out,
马上又绷紧神经
after all that he's been through,
简直是残忍又怪异的惩罚
it just seems like cruel and unusual punishment.
你难道要让女孩子主动说"抱抱我"吗
Does a girl have to come out and say, "Hold me?"
我一直很需要个拥抱
I needed this.
这个关系紧张的家缺少拥抱
There is not a lot of hugging going on in the nuclear family.
阿曼莎
Amantha?
怎么了  要我帮你吹箫吗
What-- am I smushing your droid?
阿曼莎
Amantha?
阿曼莎  我们讨论过了
Amantha, we talked about this.
人家可没有备忘簿啊
Somebody didn't get the memo.
我们有协议的
We had an agreement.
我知道
I know.
这儿不是亚特兰大  到处有媒体关注
Hey-hey, this isn't Atlanta, before the media attention.
让媒体吃屎去吧
The media sucks.
-天啊  -对了
- Oh, God... mmm... m - Oh... okay.
咱们的窗纸还没正式捅破呢
We never even had an official last poke.
不  不  不
Oh, no-no-no.
算是捅破了
We-we kinda did.
听着
Okay, look.
这次绝对会是正式的  正式的  好吗
This will be the official... official, okay?
阿曼莎  停下来
Amantha, stop.
别转头
Don't turn around.
他走了
He's gone.
我们真是白痴
We are idiots.
去吃午餐
Well, wanna get lunch?
别害羞
Hey, don't be shy.
你想回去拿多少次都行
You can go back for seconds, thirds, as much as you want here.
大家吃的比以前多啊
People eat more than I recall.
是啊
Yeah.
以前自助餐只有在周日做礼拜后才有
You know, buffets used to just be for Sundays after church.
现在什么时候都吃的到了
Now, it's seven days a week around here.
没有个自助餐就绝对称不上生意模范
Can't even really compete as a business model without one.
话说你是不是明朝的时候进去的啊
Say, was the Ming Dynasty around before you went in?
对不起
I'm sorry.
洲际公路上的中国自助餐
Chinese buffet up on the interstate.
不是
No.
在它开张的时候
You know, when it first opened,
只要3.99刀就能吃到饱
it was all you could eat for $3.99.
你这辈子都见不到
You never seen so many
那么多佐治亚州白痴
dumb Georgia crackers descendin' on egg rolls
狂吃蛋卷和糖醋里脊
and sweet and sour chicken in all your life.
听上去很有趣
That's interesting.
我猜也是
I guess.
咱俩能说实话吗
Can we be frank?
我很乐意啊
I would hope so.
你有在店里工作的计划吗
Do you plan on workin' at the store?
我没有认真考虑过  小泰
I hadn't really thought about it, Ted.
我爸要是知道
Look, my daddy'd kill me,
我跟你谈论这个  会杀了我的
if he knew we were having this conversation.
只要你一句话  他就会把店里的钥匙给你
He'd just as soon give you the keys to the store and walk away,
然后扭头就走
if that's what you wanted.
他是个好人
He's a good man.
我也会跟着他那么做
And I would, too, for that matter.
重点是  镇上有些政务
Point is, there are small town politics
跟你的那些情况
involved here with your, uh,
有点牵连
your ongoing situation and all.
有些人心里已经打定了主意
You know, some people have made up their minds about things,
而且雷打不动
and there's just nothin' that's ever gonna change 'em.
他们就像生了根一样
You know, they're just dug in.
人就是这样一种滑稽的动物
People are funny that way.
但不是  很好笑的那种滑稽
But, not "Ha-ha" funny.
什么
What?
不
No.
总之  这个时代的经济很无常
Anyway, in these uncertain economic times
再加上利润率紧缩
and tight profit margins,
我主要是在为杰瑞德的未来考虑
I mean, I'm just thinking about Jared's future, primarily.
我明白了
I see.
这实在太复杂了
It's damn complicated.
小泰德  谢谢你告诉我这些
Well, I appreciate you sharing this information with me, Ted.
信息量很大
I'm sure it's a load to carry.
话题还很敏感
Kinda sensitive, too.
你明白我的意思
You know what I mean.
我不会说的
I don't talk.
我想也是  你都经历过这么多事了
I guess not, not after everything you've been through.
吃饱了吗
You had enough?
饱了
Yes, I have.
好的
All right.
阿曼莎
Amantha?
我们不应该...
We never should've...
我不应该和委托人的妹妹有染
I never should've gotten involved with
-更别说...  -现在别做总结陈词
- a client's sister, much less... - No summation now,
拜托
please.
你们好啊
Well, hey, there.
很久不见啊  阿曼莎
Long time no see, Amantha.
我正减肥呢
Been watchin' my figure.
效果不错
Well, it shows.
你们要点今日的推荐  自选三拼吗
So, ya'll want the meat and three special?
好
Uh, sure.
给我来一块馅饼就好
I'll just have a piece of pie.
什么味道的
What kind?
无所谓
Doesn't matter.
不会让你失望的
I'll surprise you.
太棒了
Great.
上帝  我真讨厌这小镇
God, I hate this town.
你真的不想挥上一杆吗
Sure you don't wanna hit a bucket?
我宁愿看你打
I'd rather watch.
随你便
Suit yourself.
我老婆说我老爱管别人闲事
Yes, my wife says I'm nosy.
我觉得我只是好奇心旺盛罢了
I like to think of myself more as-as curious.
所以  要是我不小心越界了
So, if I happen to cross some kind of imaginary line with you,
你得告诉我
just let me know.
好
Sure.
我哥们说
So, my buddies
你在死囚牢房的时候可以有配偶探监
said you could have conjugal visits on death row.
我跟他们说这都是扯淡  传闻而已
I told 'em it was all BS, more like an urban legend.
没有什么配偶探监
There are no conjugal visits.
我就知道
I knew it!
你根本不能触碰别人  是吧
You couldn't even touch another person, right?
不能接触
No touchin'.
那能把你搞神经了吧
That's gotta work on your psyche.
本来不会这样的
You weren't supposed to, anyway.
什么叫本来
What do you mean, wasn't supposed to?
我刚下狱那会儿  情况并非如此
Things were a lot different when I was first incarcerated.
有些狱警缺乏监管
A certain element of guards were less supervised.
所以发生了一些事
So, it, uh, created an environment for things to occur.
什么...什么样的事
Things... What-what, uh, what kinda things?
应该说是遭遇吧
Encounters, I guess.
并非偶然  更像是某种开端
Well, not by chance, more like an initiation of sorts.
开端
Initiation?
是的
Yeah.
可能因为他们在你脸上第一次看到类似乐观
Maybe it was when they first saw somethin' akin to optimism
或是平和的表情吧
on your face, or a bit of peace,
或者当你开始自欺欺人地相信...
or just that moment when you began to believe that...
你能在狱里安然无恙地生存
you could survive it in some paradoxical way.
我不知道他们为什么那么做
I don't know why they did it.
为其辩解就是一种滑坡谬误啊  小泰德
Justification's a slippery slope, Ted.
利用不合理的因果关系  以达到某种意欲之结论的逻辑谬误
某天早上  你动身去洗每周一次的淋浴
So, one mornin', you go off for your weekly shower,
一群狱友突然出现
and this group of inmates with particular compulsions
态度特别蛮横
suddenly appear.
你马上就会明白他们为何会来这儿
You understand at once why they're there,
可你就是无能为力
but there's nothin' you can do about it.
你可以抗争  展现自己的男子气概
You can fight it, some symbolic gesture to your manhood,
但却无法阻止暴行
but you can't stop it.
事情就那么发生了...
So, it happens...
一而再再而三
repeatedly.
见鬼
Shit.
然后  结束了
But then, it's over.
他们来也匆匆  去也匆匆
Just as quickly as they appeared, they're gone.
这真是最怪异的事情了  小泰德
It's the strangest thing, Ted.
你又只身一人了
There you are, alone again.
水还在不停地流
The water's still runnin'.
狱警又出现了  就像根本没离开过一样
The guards reappear like they never left.
或许真的一直都在
Maybe they didn't.
我已经记不清了
I don't know now.
然后你洗完澡  穿好衣服
So, you finish your shower and get dressed.
人还没回去  消息已经传开了
Word gets back before you do.
像样点儿的人不愿再拿正眼瞧你
Decent guys on the row won't look at you now.
他们为你感到难堪
They're too embarrassed for ya.
还有些人  当你经过他们的牢房
Then, there are the ones who, when you pass by their cells,
他们用最好奇的眼神盯着你  小泰德
they look at you with the basest form of curiosity, Ted,
就好像你是畸形秀上的怪人
like you were some freak show,
而他们要看个够
and they wanna get all their money's worth,
别人的耻辱让他们尤为亢奋
because, more than anything, they're aroused by another shame.
你能明白吗
You know?
狱里还有一群特殊的人
Then, there's a very special group on the row
他们看着你的眼神就好像...
who look at you with this look, like...
我该怎么向你形容呢  小泰德
How can I describe it for ya, Ted,
怎样你才能真正理解
so you can really understand it?
好像他们可以把你拖进他们的牢房
It's like they can pull you into their cell
不仅仅对你上下其手
and not just do things to ya,
而是真真正正地吃掉你
but literally consume you,
让你窒息
take your breath,
吞噬你的心
eat your heart,
把你往死里糟蹋
and shit you out like you were nothin'.
对不起
I'm sorry.
这些事你可能无法想象
I'm sure that was more than you were.
不过世间万事  很难判定
But, it is difficult to gauge things in this world.
我想  像你这样的人
And like you, I suppose,
是很难掌握那些界限的
hard to know where the lines are.
就这样...
Anyway...
我不知道它是怎么进来的
I don't know how he got in.
你得对那小贱货采取点措施
You need to get that little son of a bitch some action.
真是太煞风景了
He's frustrated.
没办法  我都把它o阉了
I don't see how. I castrated him.
难怪它都快气死了  没完没了的
Then, he's pissed off, 24/7.
大部分时间它都很乖巧的
Most of the time, he's sweet.
很乖的
He's sweet.
你就是来速战速决的吗  议员先生
Just here for a quickie, Senator?
玛西  你在餐馆调情得注意点儿
Marcy, you need to go easy on the flirting at the cafe.
我和每个人都调情
I flirt with everybody.
警长起疑了
Sheriff's suspicious.
警察不就得疑神疑鬼的
Isn't that his job?
玛西
Marcy.
要是我不调情了  不是更让他起疑吗
If I stop flirting, won't it make him more suspicious?
你去当服务员真是太大材小用了
You are way too damn smart to be a waitress.
命运不公啊
Life isn't fair.
猜猜今天中午谁来光顾了
Guess who came in for lunch today.
我不知道  玛西
I don't know, Marcy.
斯特罗姆・瑟蒙德的鬼魂吗
The ghost of Strom Thurmond?
已故美国政客
不  那是上周的事
No, that was last week.
阿曼莎・霍顿和她那来自亚特兰大的律师
Amantha Holden and her lawyer from Atlanta.
我听说他来了
Yeah, I heard he landed.
那你听说了他们俩之间有一腿吗
Did your other source tell you that they were doin' the nasty?
你怎么知道的
How do you know that?
因为姑娘脸上那副生气的表情  一看就知道
'Cause there's a special kind of mad that a girl gets
她和那小子干过
with a boy who's diddlin' her.
这对主场队来说是好消息吗
Is that good news for the home team?
还不清楚
Well, I don't know yet,
但肯定没什么坏处
but I sure don't see how it could hurt us.
我没时间买花
I didn't have time to stop for flowers.
有这心就行了
Well, it's the thought that counts.
你到底是怎么进来的
How'd you get inside?
我们走吧
Let's go.
是他做的
He did it.
什么
What?
我相信是他做的
I believe he did it.
也许不是他一个人做的  但他肯定参与了
Maybe he wasn't alone, but he was damn sure in on it.
你为什么这么肯定
What makes you so sure?
不知道  我就是管不住自己的嘴
Oh, hell, I don't know. I'm just runnin' my mouth.
你不能突然出现
Well, you can't just come in out of the blue
就说些这种话  小泰德
and say somethin' like that, Teddy.
-老天啊  -我明白  我明白
- I mean... goodness! - I know... I know.
-你是认真的吗  -我明白  托尼
- I mean, really. - I know, Tawney!
该死  我只是想发泄一下而已
Damn, I'm just blowin' off some steam!
怎么了
Well, what happened?
今天发生了...什么事吗
Did somethin'... did somethin' happen today?
我说不清
Nothin' I can put my finger on.
他是个怪人
He's just a weird guy.
-天呐  小泰德  -我明白
- Oh, Teddy, good grief. - I know.
谁不奇怪呢  好吧  我了解
Who wouldn't be weird? All right, I get it.
不过我们吃午餐时
But, when we was at lunch,
他给我一种很不好的感觉
I just got a really bad feelin' from him.
我得找个人倾吐
I gotta share my feelings with somebody.
我又不能跟共济会
It's not like I can go
吐露这种心声
sharing my inner feelings about this down at the Masonic Lodge.
确实
No.
你能和我分享我很高兴
I-I'm glad you share with me.
你要为此祈祷吗
You wanna pray about it?
什么
What?
为我们现在生活中所发生的一切
Just about everything that's going on in our lives, right now.
我不想为任何事祈祷  托尼
I don't wanna pray about everything, Tawney,
尤其是为了他和他的烂事
especially not about him and his shit.
烤得如何啊  泰德
How's it lookin', Ted?
秘籍就在于让大家饿到不行
Secret is to make everybody so hungry,
他们就会觉得食物很美味了
they'll eat anything.
才不是呢
That's not true.
泰德是家里最好的厨师
Big Ted is the best cook in the family.
这个很花时间  对吧
I guess this could take a long time, couldn't it?
是啊
It could.
时间就是金钱
Time is money.
对政府来说就没差
Well, not so much for the government.
无论怎样都赚钱
They get paid either way.
杰瑞德他
Jared is gonna,
在接下来的几年里会需要钱的
you know, need some things over the next few years.
快上大学了
College looming.
当然
Of course.
我想知道的是
I guess, what I wanna know is,
你会不会支持我们  乔恩
are you gonna be backin' us, John?
老实说  泰德  这要司法裁决说了算
To be honest with you, Ted, that's Justice Row's call.
但是目前看来  情况很乐观
But, they're very positive, so far.
他们有没有可能放他一马
Think there's a chance in hell they'd just cut it loose?
直接放他走
You know, just let him go?
只要能从政治以及其他方面
If it's in their best interest,
迎合他们的最大利益
politically and otherwise,
万事皆有可能
anything's possible.
对我你用不着掩饰
I'm the one person around here you don't need
直说就好
to sugarcoat things for.
万事皆有可能  泰德
Anything is possible, Ted.
但  他们肯放手我才会震惊呢
But, I'd be real surprised, if they let it go.
只要合他们的意  这事几年内都没完
And they could stretch it out for years, if it suited them.
我们不是才吃过吗
Uh, didn't we just eat?
那已经是两小时前的事了
That was two hours ago,
在这儿  两小时跟半年一样长
which around here is like eight hours in dog years.
这不是小泰德和托尼吗
Well, if it isn't Teddy and Tawney.
你好  我们带了纸杯蛋糕
Hi, we-we brought cupcakes.
真好
That's nice.
还有些啤酒  可以吗
And some beer. Is that all right?
只要你答应别用猎枪打瓶子玩
Long as you promise not to shotgun 'em.
对了  我爱吃猪肉
Well, you know, I am a pork eater, just for the record.
爱吃啥都随你点
I just do what I'm told.
我已经学会自己做猪排了
I've been known to cook up some baby back ribs myself.
悠着点儿
Oh, be careful now.
一开始  你只是吃吃猪肉三明治
First, you're eatin' a pork sandwich.
接着你就在喝耶稣的宝血了
Next thing you know, you're drinkin' the blood of Jesus.
传说耶稣的血有赦罪的功效  调侃乔恩会犯罪坐牢
小泰德
Teddy!
我只是和他开开玩笑
I'm just kiddin' with him.
轮到你了
Your turn.
我去趟商店  很快回来
Hey, uh, I'm runnin' to the store. I'll be right back.
妈妈
Mom?
都准备好了
Everything's ready.
好极了
Great.
妈妈
Mom?
怎么了  阿曼莎
Yes, Amantha?
我也不知道
I don't know.
要我帮忙拿什么东西吗
Can I get somethin'?
拿卷心菜沙拉吧
The slaw.
好的
Okay.
丹尼  小子
Hey, Danny, boy!
早上好啊
Top of the mornin' to ya.
丹尼  我知道你醒了
Ah... I know you're awake, Danny.
你一直都醒着
Ah... you're always awake.
你知道  你以为你会厌倦
You know, you'd think you'd get tired of
年复一年地靠同一段记忆来打飞机
making pancake batter to the same memory, year after year.
但其实不然
Ain't happened yet.
好吧
Okay.
如果你没有勒死我们的小甜心汉娜
So, uh, if you didn't strangle the life out of our sweet Hannah,
你打算怎么泄欲
what do you bust a load to, huh?
是回忆冰淇淋性爱
Memories of ice cream?
还是去舞会猎艳
Prom?
没准我刚才激射的时候
Maybe you just get the shivers
你也跟着爽了下吧
from me gettin' the shivers.
也许你只体会到了性快感
Maybe that's all you got.
为什么总是我们女人在收拾
Why are we the only ones cleaning up, again?
阿曼莎  这是老黄历的传统了
It's the 1950's, Amantha.
你也搞不懂原因
You just don't know it.
老爸  猪排烤得可真不错
Them were some damn fine ribs, daddy.
谢谢夸奖  小泰
Thank you, Teddy.
是啊  的确不错  老爸
Yeah-- sure were, pop.
小子  你才吃了一块
You only ate one there, boy.
我就想尝一块
That's all I wanted.
杰瑞德  你现在不要求我们吃素了吧
You ain't going vegan on us now, are ya, Jared?
不了
No.
大伙  没什么其他安排了吧
Hey, there's not anything else planned, is there?
我得开溜了
I'm gonna have to scoot in a minute.
安排  你指什么
Planned-- like what?
我也不知道
I don't know.
给你来个授牌仪式吗
Like a plaque presentation?
阿曼莎  我就是不知道才问的嘛
I don't know, Amantha. That's why I'm asking.
没安排了
No.
吃完派就结束了
The pie was it.
说到这个  珍妮特  派很好吃
Oh, speaking of, that was excellent pie, Janet.
谢谢夸奖  小泰
Thank you, Teddy.
我来帮你拿
Oh, let me get that.
谢谢
Thank you.
你能先去拿好东西吗
Hey, you wanna go ahead and, uh, grab your stuff?
我马上就回来
I'll be right back.
你好
Hello.
抱歉我还没怎么和你说过话
I'm sorry I haven't said more to you.
我想我还是有点害怕
I guess I was afraid.
不是害怕你  只是不知道要说什么
Not of you-- I just didn't know what to say, exactly.
我理解
I understand.
但我很开心你能回来  回到家里
But, I'm glad you're here, home.
谢谢
Thank you.
我也很开心
I-I'm glad, too.
如果你乐意的话  来坐会儿
Please, take a seat, if you'd like.
今天真是个好日子啊
Sure is a beautiful day.
今天...
It, um,
很多姿多彩
has lots of colors.
丹尼尔  你最喜欢哪个季节
Do you have, like, a-a favorite season, Daniel?
最喜欢的季节吗
A favorite season?
我个人很喜欢秋天
Personally, I like the fall a lot.
但我也非常喜爱仲夏的雨
But also, I love it when it rains on a hot summer day,
虽然严格说来这并不是一个季节
even though that's technically not a season.
你为什么喜欢仲夏的雨
What is it that you love about rain on a hot summer's day?
我也不知道...
I don't know...
它能让我平静下来
calms me down.
让植物也更有生气
Makes the plants happy.
还有打雷  我也很喜欢打雷
And the thunder, I love the thunder.
这让我想到上帝  并不是往坏的方向想
It makes me think of God, but not in a bad way.
那你呢
What is it?
我意识到我脑海里想起的大多数事物
I'm just so aware that most of what I draw on from inside my head
都是源于我所读到的
are things I've read about.
我真实的生活经历其实非常贫乏
My real life experiences are actually rather narrow.
我有很长一段时间
I don't think about the seasons,
没去想过季节了
not for the longest time anyway.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
我并不想装可怜
I don't mean to sound pitiful.
不  没有  你没有
No, oh, no, you don't, not really.
我并没有那种感觉  为自己难过
I don't feel that way-- sorry for myself.
我感到有时候别人会这样看待我
I do feel I am being received sometimes that way by others.
我也知道自己有时也会那么觉得
And I know I have a part in that somehow.
只是还没有理清头绪
I just don't have it figured out yet.
这也许会花些时间...来理清头绪
That'll probably take some time-- figurin' things out.
你怎么想
What is it?
我原先住的地方没有窗户
The place where I was had no windows.
一堵厚墙包围着一堵厚墙
Just these thick walls surrounded by more thick walls.
所以  我永远都不知道
So, I never knew if it was
外面是否在下雨  再大的雷声也听不到
rainin' or even heard the loudest thunder.
太伤感了
It's so sad.
这并没有听着的那么伤感  因为我
Oh, it's-it's not as bad as it sounds, because I-I didn't
不是以普通的方式来感知事物
sense things in a normal way.
我并不想念它们
I didn't miss them.
如果我不能感知到他们
If-if I couldn't sense them,
我...他们对我而言就不是真实的
I-I-- they weren't real to me.
丹尼尔  对你而言  什么是真实的
What was real to you, Daniel?
分分秒秒的时间
The time in between the seconds.
以及我的书...
And my books...
还有我的朋友
and my friend.
如今我在这个世界里
Now that I'm here in this world,
所有的事物都被时间  日期或事件所标记
where everything's marked by hours, or dates, or events,
我发现我自己一直处于一种期待状态
I find myself in a state of constant anticipation.
我并不确定我在期待什么
What it is I'm anticipatin', I'm not always sure,
这也并不必然是一种愉悦的感受
nor is it necessarily a pleasant feelin'.
但至于无法避免的下雨和打雷
But, in the case of the inevitable rain and thunder,
我也必将去经历
which I am sure to experience,
谢谢你  托尼
thanks to you, Tawney,
我很期待
I am very much looking forward to that.
一定会非常愉快  丹尼尔
It will be glorious, Daniel.
你不会失望的
You won't be disappointed.
丹尼尔
Daniel?
我们会有更多交流机会的
We'll have more conversations.
我很期待
I look forward to that.
该走了吗
It's time to go?
是啊
Yeah.
我会去车里找你
I'll meet you out in the car.
好的
Okay.
听着
Uh, listen.
你今天在午餐后告诉我的一切
All that stuff you told me today after lunch,
我不知道你是不是在和我开玩笑
I don't know if you was pulling my leg or not.
泰德  我为什么要和你开玩笑
Why would I pull your leg, Ted?
我也不知道
I don't know.
类似玩游戏吗
Like a game?
不
No.
你玩游戏吗  泰德
Do you play games, Ted?
我只是不理解那个世界
It's just not a world I understand.
不管怎样  也许我这么做很傻很鲁莽
Anyway, um, well, this may be stupid of me, or crass,
但我给你找了些乐子
but, uh, I got you a little eye candy.
这些能帮你
A little somethin' to help you, uh,
你懂得  过渡到监狱外的世界来
you know, transition into the outside world.
让你回归正常
You know, get your mind right.
你在和外星人谈什么呢
What was you and star man talkin' about?
天气
The weather.
火星上的天气吗
On Mars?
不是
No.
你知道吗  他在监狱里连打雷都听不到
You know, he didn't even hear thunder while he was in there.
连个窗户都没有
Didn't even have a window.
亲爱的  他可是住在死囚室
Darlin', he was on death row.
监狱可不管他能看到什么
He's not guaranteed a view.
我知道
I know.
这也太...我也不知道
It just seemed-- I don't know.
你们谈了些什么
What'd ya'll talk about?
没什么
Nothin'.
我送了他一个回家礼物
I just gave him a homecoming gift.
你送了...什么
You did-- what?
色情杂志
Dirty magazine.
不会吧
You did not!
为什么不
Why not?
我不知道
I don't know.
只是显得俗气了些
Just seems tacky or somethin'.
他回家连个老婆或女朋友都没有
Hey, he doesn't have a wife or girlfriend to come home to.
他需要一些放松
He needs some kind of release.
如果他打飞机打个几百次
Maybe if he chokes that chicken a few hundred times,
他就不会表现的那么诡异了
he won't be so weird acting.
你老说他诡异  但  我并不...
You keep saying he's weird, but, you know, I don't--
我并不这么觉得  真的
I don't see it that way, really.
他就是诡异
Oh, he's weird.
天呐
Goodness!
你一直在看我吗
You've been lookin' at me?
是啊  我一直看着你呢
Yeah, I've been lookin' at ya.
你是我妻子
You're my wife.
难道我还不能看吗
Can't I look at ya?
好吧  好吧
Yeah, yeah.
我只是  只是不知道你在看着我
I just-I just didn't-- I didn't know you were lookin' at me.
好吧  我试着转头不看  但你太美了
Well, I tried to turn away, but you're just so beautiful.
我无法转移视线
I couldn't take my eyes off of you.
好吧  谢了  小泰
Well, thank you, Teddy.
你怎么还遮着
Why are you still covered up?
我不知道
I don't know.
因为我  我不知道你在看着我
Um, 'cause I just-I just-- I didn't know you were lookin' at me.
你懂得  我正打算洗澡
And, you know, I-I was just planning on taking bath,
没想到你就这么进来对着我
and I didn't expect you to come in on me like this.
我有些小尴尬
And, um, I'm a little embarrassed.
为什么
Why?
这又不是罪过
It isn't a sin.
我们是夫妻啊
We're man and wife.
我知道
I know.
让我看看你
Let me see ya.
来吧  托尼
Come on, Tawney.
让我看一眼嘛
Let Teddy have a little peek.
好吧
Okay.
你都看过了
You've had your look.
我现在能去洗澡了吗
Now, can I take my bath?
当然  如果你想去的话
Yeah, sure-- if that's what you want.
你不介意的话  我要去洗澡了
It is, if you wouldn't mind.
丹尼尔出狱后  我们就没做过爱了
You know, we haven't made love since Daniel got out.
所以呢
So?
也许只是巧合
Maybe it's just coincidence.
你什么意思
What do you mean?
我不知道
I don't know.
我猜想你可能对他
I thought maybe you had some kinda-kind of
有所爱慕什么的
big crush on him or somethin'.
别犯傻了
Don't be silly.
你居然这么说让我很生气
I'm offended you would even suggest that.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
你知道我有时会缺乏安全感
You know I get a little insecure sometimes.
好好洗澡吧
Enjoy your bath.